Finding Aid for the Thomas J Hogan Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Thomas J Hogan Collection
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0726
15.54 linear feet
Biographical Note
Thomas J. Hogan, J.D. is a graduate of Vanderbilt University’s College of Arts and Sciences from Boston, Massachusetts. He donated his family collection of historically significant newspapers on September 8, 2010.
Scope and Content Note
The Thomas J. Hogan collection (15.54 linear feet) is comprised of newspapers, magazines, photographs, and other pamphlets and publications from 1962-1977. The biggest portion of them are from The New York Times, but other publications are represented. The collection is intended to serve mainly as research materials for political science and history professors and their students.
- John F. Kennedy Assassination Newspapers, (November 1963 – November 1964)
  - November 23 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    The New York Times
  - November 1963 – November 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Patterson Evening News
    Post Daily Magazine
    New York World Telegram and Sun
- Magazines relating to the Kennedys, (July 1962 – August 1969)
  - Life Magazine (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Look Magazine (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sunday News (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Moon Landing Newspapers, (July 13 – 21, 1969)
  - July 13-16 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Sunday Record Call Special Section
    The Record
  - July 20-21 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Sunday Record Call
- Moon Landing Newspapers, (July 22 -24, 1969)
  - July 22 1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - July 23-24 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- NASA Pamphlets, Museum Programs and Photos, (1966 -1967)
  - Communications Satellites, (1966) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Project Gemini, (1966) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Marshall Space Flight Center, (1967) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Richard Nixon and Watergate, (October 1971 – August 1974)
  - October 1971 – October 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - August 9-10 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    The Star Ledger
- Bicentennial Newspapers and Magazines, (July 4-5, 1976)
  - Newspapers (July 4 1976) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers (July 5 1976) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Magazines (July 4-5 1976) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Newsweek
    The Sunday News
    Time Magazine
- Miscellaneous Newspapers, Clippings, and Ads, (1963-1977)
  - April 1964 – April 1967 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Journal American (General McArthur)
    The New York Times (Ford’s 2nd Inauguration,
    World Journal Tribune (World Series)
    Daily News (NJ Chemical Plant Blast)
    The Record (Equal Housing)
  - September 1971 – October 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    The New York Times (Attica Prison, World Series)
  - November 1973 – November 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    The Ridgewood News (Glen Rock)
    The New York Times (Jimmy Carter)
- Miscellaneous Magazines, (1962-1977)
  - NYT Magazine (Land Reform in Venezuela) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Look Magazine (Youth ’66, Cars, White House) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Life (Moon Landing, Super Bowl, Israeli Olympic Tragedy, Diana Ross, 1972 in Pictures, 1977 in Pictures) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Time Magazine (Astronaut Splashdown) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Sunday Times Magazine (Famous American Families) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - New York Magazine (Box 9, Folder 6)